看看我的水杯，多恶心啊
check out my water bottle, how sick is that
你们好，欢迎回到这个批渲染迷你系列
what's up you guys, welcome back to the batch rendering mini series
那么上一次，我们了解了顶点颜色
so last time, we took a look at vertex colors
以及我们如何将颜色加入到批渲染中
and how we can get colors into our batch rendering situation
如果你们还没看过那个视频，不妨看看
check out that video, if you haven't already
如果你们是这个系列的新手，不知道到底发生了什么
and if you're new to this series, and you don't know what on earth is going on
然后去看看这个系列的第一个视频
then check out the first video in the series
我们在纸上看看批渲染的原理，为什么它有用
where we take a look on paper at how batch rendering actually works, and why it's useful
今天我们要讨论纹理
today we're going to be talking about textures
现在，批渲染和纹理看起来似乎并没有很好地结合在一起
now, batch rendering and textures might seem like they don't really go together very well
因为通常你们所习惯的只是简单地建立一个纹理
because usually what you're probably used to is simply setting up a texture
为特定的纹理槽激活它
activating it for a particular texture slot
然后发出一个DrawCall，在你们的着色器中，从纹理统一变量中采样
and then issuing a DrawCall, and in your shader, sampling from the texture uniform
你们已经上传到着色器的采样器，那就很不错了
sampler that you've actually uploaded to the shader, and that's all fine
那样做没有什么错
there's nothing wrong with doing that
并且那就是你们如何渲染3D模型的很多方法，任何你们真正渲染的东西
and that's a lot of how you would render 3D models quads, anything that you're really rendering
然而，在批渲染中，我们似乎失去了这种功能
however, with batch rendering, we kind of lose that functionality
因为同样的原因，我们失去了整个颜色功能
for the same reason that we lose this whole color functionality
我们不能再像以前那样有颜色的统一变量了
we can't have a uniform color anymore like we used to be able to do
因为我们所拥有的和我们所面临的限制是
because what we have and the limitation we're working with is
事实上，我们场景中的每一个四边形，每一个物体或实体
the fact that every single quad, every single object or entity in our scene
现在被渲染在一个独立的DrawCall
is now being rendered in a single DrawCall
我们没有DrawCall，DrawCall，DrawCall
we don't have DrawCall, DrawCall, DrawCall
这意味着我们可以插入统一变量DrawCall...
which means that we can insert uniform DrawCall, uniform DrawCall, uniform DrawCall
我们不能再这样做了，不能在那些DrawCall中插入统一变量
we can't do that anymore, we can't insert uniforms amongst those DrawCalls
或者我应该说
or I should say
就像在DrawCall之中，提交和上传统一变量一样
like uniform submissions uniform uploads amongst those DrawCall
我们不能再那么做了，因为所有东西是用独立DrawCall来绘制的
we can't do that anymore, because everything's being drawn with a single DrawCall
这很好，那就是把东西组合在一起的意义
which is wonderful, that's the whole point of batching things together
让我们考虑一下纹理，我们如何将纹理很好地组合在一起
so let's consider textures, how can we batch together textures well
说到将纹理批量处理，你们可能马上想到的一种方法是
just by saying batch together textures, one of the ways that you might think of immediately is
如果我们的纹理包含多个纹理呢
well, what if our texture contained more than one texture
现在，这就像是跳出固有的思维模式进行深入思考
now, this is really like getting deep thinking outside the box
不管你们怎么称呼它，我们如何将纹理批量处理
whatever you want to call it, how can we batch together textures
我们能做的是制作纹理图集或表格
well what we could do is make something called a texture atlas or a sprite sheet
它们在游戏中非常常用，特别是在那些低保真度低分辨率的游戏中
they're very commonly used in games, especially in games that have kind of low fidelity low resolution
我会说渲染动作是一个低保真度
I'll say render actions a low fidelity
因为它仍然可能是视觉上相当高的质量
because it still might be visually quite high quality
但是渲染本身和它所作用的纹理可能低于分辨率
but the rendering itself and the textures that it acts upon might below resolution
我想到了《我的世界》或者《Stardew Valley》就是一个很好的例子
so something like minecraft comes to mind or like you know Stardew Valley again is a good example
它们的纹理分辨率都很低，比如所有的贴图，或者所有的砖块
they have rather low resolution textures for like all of the tiles, or in microft all of the blocks
正因为如此，简单地将纹理组合在一起是非常容易的
so because of that, it's very easy to simply batch together the textures
如果每个纹理都是16x16像素，那么就不会有10个不同的纹理, cluella
if each texture is like 16 by 16 pixels, then instead of having 10 different textures, cluella
我们将不得不去看看她，如果每个纹理只有16x16像素
we'll have to check her out, if each texture is only 16 by 16 pixels
那么，为什么我们会有10个不同的纹理，每个都是16x16
then why would we have 10 separate textures that are each 16 by 16
相反，我们可以很容易地将它们组合在一起
instead of doing that we could easily batch it together
那只会是一个，那会是什么
and it would only be like a, what's that gonna be
我们就说，128×128的纹理
let's just say, one twenty eight by one twenty eight texture
对，这将会是一个非常低分辨率的纹理
right, it's gonna be so gonna be quite a lower resolution texture
它包含了里面所有的纹理就像子纹理一样
and it just contains all of the kind of textures inside it almost like sub textures
然后如果我们想要渲染那些，我们所要做的就是思考
and then if we want to actually render those, then all we have to do is think about
我们实际的纹理坐标是如何设置的
how our actual texture coordinates are set up
所以不是用纹理坐标采样所有的纹理
so instead of just sampling all of our textures with texture coordinates
0 2 1是整个纹理，我们可以缩小这个范围
0 2 1 which would be the entire texture, we can reduce this range
然后处理一个子集来选择那个纹理的子区域
and kind of deal with like a subset essentially to select a sub region of that texture
这是非常常见的做法，而且肯定会在OpenGL系列中进行探讨
very commonly done, and definitely something will explore in the OpenGL series, at some point
但是，那不是我们解决这个问题的方法
however, that's not how we're going to solve this
因为在这种情况下，我们仍然会有不同的纹理
because in this case, we are still actually going to have separate textures
原因是我们可能想把它们堆在一起，它们不是单独的纹理
the reason is maybe we want to batch these together, and they're not in separate texture
现在我们要把它们组合成一个纹理，那可能很有用
so what we have to combine them into one texture now, that might be useful
例如，如果输入字体和文本，你们知道的
for example if you're entering like fonts and text, you know
你们基本上会有这种纹理图集和所有的字体字符
you would basically have this kind of texture atlas with all of your font characters
然后就像我提到的另一个方面
and then on the other side as I mentioned
如果你们有像《我的世界》那样的低分辨率纹理
if you've got low resolution textures like minecraft osaji valley
也许那也会有用，但这是更一般的情况
then maybe that would also be useful, but this is going to be much more of a general case of
我们如何渲染使用多个纹理的东西
how do we render something in wonderful that uses multiple textures
现在想想这个，想想我们是如何解决颜色的，颜色是个统一变量
now to think about this, think about how we solves colors, colors were something that were a uniform
但后来我们意识到我们不能使用统一变量，所以我们该怎么办
but then we realized we couldn't use uniforms, so what do we do
我们把颜色数据放到顶点缓冲区，对吧
where do we stick that color data into the vertex buffer, right
我们能对纹理做同样的事吗，我们不能把纹理放进顶点缓冲区
so can we do the same thing with textures, well, we can't really put a texture into a vertex buffer
然而，我们可以做的是给每个顶点缓冲区内的四边形分配某种id
however what we can do is still assign some kind of id to each quad that is inside that vertex buffer
尽管我们以后可能会在片段着色器中使用
though we can then maybe later use in the fragment shader
或者在像素着色器中选择一个纹理
or in the pixel shader to select one of the textures
这之所以行得通是因为谁说过，我们一次只需要绑定一个纹理
and the reason this works is because who says, we have to only bind one texture at once
我们实际上有很多纹理槽，这取决于你们的硬件和GPU
we don't, we actually have many texture slots, and depending on your hardware and your GPU
无论你们是在电脑上还是手机上
and whether you're on like pc or like a phone or something
你们会有不同数量的纹理槽
you will have a varying amount of texture slots
例如，这台电脑有32个纹理槽
and for example, this computer here has 32 texture slots
那意味着我可以同时拥有32种不同的纹理
that means I can have 32 different textures bound at the same time
然后从我感兴趣的地方取样，那是完全可行的
and then just sample from the one that I'm interested in, that's totally totally doable
那么这个的工作方式就是进入顶点缓冲区
so then the way this is going to work is into the vertex buffer
对于我们渲染的每一个实际的正方形，和我们渲染颜色的方法是一样的
for each actual quad that we render, the same way that we did with color
我们将提供一些额外的信息
we're going to supply some additional information
在这个例子中，我们提供的数据是一个索引
and in this case, the data we're supplying is going to be an index
并且索引是0或1或2
an index being like zero or one or two
接下来会发生的是，我们会传递那个数据
and then what's going to happen is we're going to pass that data
在渲染这个特定的四边形时，从顶点着色器到片段着色器的索引
that index from our vertex shader into the fragment shader, upon rendering this specific quad
然后片段着色器会使用那个索引
and then the fragment shader is going to use that index
作为纹理数组和采样数组统一变量的索引，以这种方式
as an index into an array of textures and array of uniform samplers, and in that way
我们可以说这个四边形的渲染索引应该是0，纹理索引是0
we can basically say that this quad should be rendered with index zero texture index zero
另一个四边形应该使用纹理索引1进行渲染
this other quad should be rendered with texture index one
然后在我的片段着色器中，我简单地从正确的纹理取样
and then in my fragment shader, I simply sample from the right texture
通过使用它作为纹理采样器数组的索引
by just using it as an index into an array of texture samplers
这一点都不复杂，我们将深入研究一些代码
it's really not that complicated at all, we're going to dive into some code
我们来看看，如何重新设计它，事实上
and we're going to take a look, at how we can actually redesign this, and in fact
我们引入纹理的事实比实际情况要复杂得多
that the fact that we're introducing textures to this is going to be more complex than the fact
我们需要在实际的顶点缓冲区中包含所有这些索引
that we need to kind of include all these indices in the actual vertex buffer
因为我的意思是，我们需要现在加载一个纹理
because I mean we have to like load a texture now
然后把它上传到我们的GPU
and then upload it to our GPU
我们需要提供纹理坐标，这些都是纹理带来的开销
we need to supply texture coordinates, there's all this kind of overhead that comes on with textures
但是我们要试着简单地讲一下，因为它不那么重要
but we're going to try and kind of breeze through that, because it's not as important
如果你们不知道纹理在OpenGL中是如何工作的
if you don't know how textures work in OpenGL
请查看OpenGL系列中的视频
check out the video in the OpenGL series about that
我们将会特别关注批渲染的部分
and we're going to just kind of focus on specifically the batch rendering part of that
这本质上是与绑定纹理到不同的槽
which is essentially to do with just binding textures to different slots
然后把索引放在顶点缓冲区中
and then having that index inside our vertex buffer
好了，我要做的第一件事是写这个LoadTexture函数
okay, so the first thing that I'm going to do is write this LoadTexture function
这将是一个非常基本的函数，它只从给定的路径加载纹理
this is going to be a pretty basic function that just loads the texture from a given path
然后返回给我们OpenGL id
and then returns to us the OpenGL id
这个函数会允许我们加载我们的两个纹理
and this function is just going to allow us to load our two textures here that we have
也就是cherno标志和hazel标志，这将是我们加载的两个样本纹理
the cherno logo and the hazel logo, those are going to be our two sample textures that we load
所以我可以到这里，进入OnAttach函数，然后简单地加载它们
so I can just come down here, into the OnAttach function and simply load them
我要给result赋值
I'm going to assign the result
也就是这两个无符号整数的OpenGL纹理id
which of course is the OpenGL texture id to these two unsigned integers
我们需要的另一个东西是这两个四边形的纹理坐标
the other thing that we're going to need are the texture coordinates of these two quads
我们会把纹理坐标放在这个颜色后面，我们有位置，我们有颜色
we'll put the texture coordinates after this color here, so we have the position, we have the color
然后我们会有每个顶点的纹理坐标，现在我们已经做了那个
and then we're going to have the texture coordinates for each vertex, and now that we've done that
我们到这里来，为这些纹理坐标设置顶点属性
we're just going to come over here, and set up the vertex attribute for these texture coordinates
我们把它设为索引2，当然它是两个浮点数
so we'll set it up at index two, and of course it's going to be two floats
我们还必须调整这里的步幅，现在总共是9个浮点数
we'll have to also adjust our strides here to be nine floats now total
然后这个的偏移量当然也是28字节
and then the offset of this is also going to be 28 bytes of course
现在我们有了这个顶点缓冲区，它能够渲染纹理
so now we have this whole kind of vertex buffer here, that is capable of rendering textures
我们真正需要做的就是到这里来
all we really need to do to make this possible is just go over here
在我们的着色器中修改我们的着色器，使它们支持这些新的纹理坐标
into our shaders and actually modify our shaders, so that they support these new texture coordinates
那么我要在这里添加这个属性，然后和颜色一样
so I'm just going to add this attribute here, and then just like with our colors
我要设置这个out变量来获得片段着色器的纹理坐标
I'm going to set up this out variable to get this texture coordinate to our fragment shader
然后我们可以通过输出纹理坐标作为颜色来测试它
and then we might as well test it by just outputting the texture coordinate as the color
并且这里我们有两个四边形有正确的纹理坐标
and here we have our two quads with the correct texture coordinates
那么现在我们已经做了所有的准备工作
so now that we've done all of this setup stuff
我们实际上可以进入我们如何渲染这些纹理时，他们被批处理绑在一起
we can actually get into how we render these textures when they're batched together
正如我提到的，我们真正需要做的是扩展我们的顶点缓冲区
so as I mentioned, what we really need to do here is extend our vertex buffer
这样每个顶点都包含一个纹理索引
so that every vertex actually includes a texture index
我们来做这个，让第一个四边形成为第一个纹理
so let's do this, let's make the first quad here be the first texture
在这种情况下，就是thecherno的标志
which in this case will be thecherno logo
然后我们会让第二个四边形是第二个纹理，也就是hazel的logo
and then we'll make the second quad here be the second texture, which is going to be the hazel logo
换句话说，第一个四边形的纹理id是0，索引是0
so in other words, the first quad is going to have a texture id of zero, index zero
然后第二个四边形会有一个纹理索引或id为1
and then the second quad is going to have a texture index or an id of one
你们可以看到，我只是添加了0作为所有这些顶点的纹理索引
and you can see that I've literally just added that zero in as the texture index for all of these vertices
然后对于这些顶点，我们应该组成第二个四边形
and then for these vertices, we should make up the second quad
我们只是有一个纹理索引1，所以现在我们有一个0和1
we simply have a texture index of one, so now we have a zero and one
就像任何属性一样
like with any attribute
现在我需要在这里用OpenGL设置属性，所以这个属性将在索引3处
I now need to set up the attribute with OpenGL here, so this attribute will be at index three
它是一个独立浮点数，然后我将设置偏移和调整像之前的步幅
it's a single float, and then I'll set the offset and adjust the stride like before
很好，那么现在每个四边形都有一个纹理索引
okay cool, so now every quad has a texture index
这可能和你们用的颜色有冲突
now this might conflict with the colors that you're using
换句话说，如果我想渲染颜色而不是纹理呢
which in other words, just means what if I want to render the color and not a texture
怎么做呢，一个常见的解法
how do I do that, well, a common way to solve that
将这种纹理槽0保留为完全没有纹理
would just be to reserve this kind of texture slot zero as no texture at all
然后one和on会与给定的纹理id相关联
and then one and on would kind of correlate to a given texture id
然后你们只需要将你们的纹理索引偏移一倍
and then you just need to offset your texture index by a factor of one
在你们的着色器中计算出实际的纹理id，如果它不为零
in your shader to work out the actual texture id, if it's not zero
但我们今天不用担心那个
but we're not gonna worry about that today
我们会用纹理0和纹理1来渲染这两个四边形
we're just gonna just render both of these quads with texture zero and texture one
现在如果我们进入着色器，让我们引入这个新属性
so now if we come over into our shader, let's take in this new attribute
这次它是一个浮点数，当然，我们将它传递到我们的片段着色器
this time it's a float, of course and we'll pass it into our fragment shader
和我们处理纹理坐标的方法一样
the same way that we did with the texture coordinate
现在作为一个有趣的活动，让我们通过输出颜色来测试它
and now as a little fun activity, let's test it out by just outputting it as the color
所以我们应该得到黑色或白色，取决于纹理索引是0还是1
so we should get either black or white, depending on if the texture index is zero or one
你们可以看到，左边的四边形实际上是黑色的
and as you can see, the quad on the left is in fact black
这意味着它的纹理索引是0
meaning it's got a texture index of zero
然后右边的四边形是白色的，这意味着它的纹理索引是1，漂亮
and then the quad on the right is white, meaning it has a texture index of one, beautiful
那么最后一步非常简单，我们需要做的就是回到这里
so now the last step is super simple, all we really need to do is go back here
然后简单地将这些纹理绑定到正确的纹理槽
and simply bind these textures to the correct texture slots
然后在我们的片段着色器中设置一些代码，从这些纹理中实际取样
and then set up some code inside our fragment shader to actually sample from these textures
所以在渲染之前，首先将这些绑定到正确的纹理槽
so first to bind these to the right texture slots before rendering
我们将简单地调用glBindTextureUnit，其索引0是thecherno纹理
we'll simply call glBindTextureUnit with index zero for thecherno texture
然后索引1就是hazel纹理
and then index one for the hazel texture
现在这些直接对应于我们在顶点缓冲区中的内容
so now these correspond directly to what we've put inside our vertex buffer
我们需要设置那个
we need to actually set up that
采样器数组，这样我们就可以对这些纹理进行采样
sampler array inside our shader, so that we can actually sample these textures
因为我们这里只有两个纹理，我把它的大小设为2
and so since we've just got two textures here, I'll just give it a size of two
现在我们有了统一采样2D数组，叫做u_Textures
so now we have this uniform sampler 2D array called u_Textures
然后我们当然需要将这个统一变量设置为我们想要取样的纹理单元
and then we of course need to set this uniform to be the texture units that we want to sample from
所以这就像一个升序列表
so this will literally just be like an ascending list
从0一直到你们的最大纹理槽数
from zero all the way to whatever your maximum texture slot is
所以在这种情况下，这两个，就是0和1
so in this case, with these two, it'll just be 0 1
如果我们有30个纹理，它将从0到29
if we had 30 textures, it would be zero through 29
最后回到我们的着色器，而不是仅仅输出颜色作为纹理索引
and finally back in our shader, instead of just outputting the color as the texture index
我们需要从这个u_Textures数组中采样
we need to sample from this u_Textures array
所以我们在片段着色器中做的第一件事
so the first thing that we'll do inside our fragment shader
就是转换这个索引成一个整数
is convert this v tax index into an integer
因为我们想把它用作数组下标，所以它必须是int型
because since we want to use it as an array index, it has to be an int
一旦我们这样完成了那个，就像
and then once we've done that, it's just as simple as
用我们的纹理坐标，根据索引选取正确的纹理进行采样
sampling the correct texture based on whatever that index is, with our texture coordinates
就是那样，你们可以看到，如果我们运行这个，我们现在有两个四边形
and that's it, as you can see, if we launch this, we now have both of these quads
在单个DrawCall中，将不同纹理分配给不同纹理槽进行渲染
rendering with different textures assigned to different texture slots in a single DrawCall
很酷的东西，事实上，你们当然可以把它扩展到
pretty cool stuff, and in fact, you can of course expand this to
你们的设备和硬件支持的纹理插槽数量
as many texture slots as your device and your hardware supports
好了，我希望那有意义，我的意思是这不是特别
okay, so I hope that that made sense, I mean it's not particularly
比如这是一个很难理解的概念
like a very challenging concept to understand, I think
但是还有一些额外的事情你们需要考虑
but there are some extra things you need to think about
例如，如果我们有，让我们看看
for example, what if we do have, let's just see
你们可能在手机上，它可能只有8个纹理槽
you might be on a phone and it might only have eight texture slots
但是你们想要渲染一些可能使用超过八个纹理的东西
but you want to render something that might use more than eight textures
我的意思是，也许你们想渲染有100个纹理的贴图地图
I mean maybe you want to render this whole tile map that has 100 textures
显然有这个限制，你们可以通过使用一些OpenGL函数来查询和发现
there's clearly this limitation which you can query and find out by using some OpenGL functions
但是我们如何处理它的局限性，答案是你们仍然可以批渲染
but how do we deal with the limitation of that, and the answer is you still can
只是你们得把这批渲染拆分
it's just that you're going to have to break up your batch
不像我们到目前为止所做的那样，在单个DrawCall中渲染所有内容
so instead of rendering everything in a single DrawCall, like we kind of have been doing so far
如果你们想为100个四边形使用100个纹理，那么基于最大纹理槽
if you want to use 100 textures for 100 quads, then based on that maximum texture slot
比如不管它是什么值，假设它是32
like value whatever it is, let's just say, it's 32
每次你们在渲染器中使用所有的32个纹理
every time you end up using all of your 32 textures loss in a renderer
当你们提交越来越多的几何图形，以渲染不同的纹理
as you submit more and more geometry to be rendered with different textures
你们可以简单地触发三下，就像这一批就结束了
you can simply once you hit three too be like that's the end of this batch
我需要刷新这个，我需要把它渲染到屏幕上
I need to flush this, I need to render it to the screen
然后我要开始一个新的批处理
and then I'm gonna begin a new batch
我的意思是你们仍然可以省下很多DrawCall的资源
and that way I mean you're still gonna save obviously on a lot of DrawCalls
因为不是像渲染100个独立的四边形和独立的纹理
because instead of rendering like 100 separate quads with separate textures
你们最终会得到100 / 32
you're going to wind up rendering my hundred of over by 32
换句话说，一组是32，另一组是32
so in other words, they'll have one group of 32, another group of 32
另一组是32个，剩下的就是最后一组
another group of 32, and then finally another group of like
我们最后只用了4次，对吧
what do we end up with like four or something like that, right
所以这仍然只需要4次而不是100次，节省了很多
so that's still gonna be only four draw calls instead of like 100, so huge saving
并且随着我们这个系列的继续，我们将会设计这个渲染器
and as we kind of move on with this series, we're gonna get to kind of designing this renderer
它可以渲染100种不同的纹理，做所有那些事情
that can render like 100 different textures, and doing all of that stuff
所以别担心，那东西会来的
so don't worry, that stuff is coming
事实上，我们现在所做的是，基本上已经涵盖了所有的基础
and in fact what we've done right now is we've basically covered all of our bases
我的意思是，我们现在可以渲染任何四边形，无论是颜色还是纹理
I mean we can now render any quad whether it be a color or a texture
我们可以在一个单独的DrawCall中渲染尽可能多的它们
and we can render as many of them as we want in a single DrawCall
所以现在我们需要做的是
so now what we need to be able to do is
没有一个静态的顶点缓冲区，它只包含前面的所有内容
not have a static kind of vertex buffer that just contains everything up front
但我想做的是能够
but what I want to do is be is to have the ability
改变所有四边形的位置
of actually changing all of these positions of all of the quads
基本上，实际就是把它们当成是
basically having them as if they were in fact
提交为独立的四边形的DrawCall和独立转换等等
submitted as separate quad separate DrawCalls with separate transforms and all of that
我希望能够随意添加和删除四边形
and I want to be able to just add and remove quads at will
这是我现在不能做的，因为我们的顶点缓冲区是静态的
which is something that I can't really do at the moment, because our vertex buffer is static
下次，我们会探讨动态顶点缓冲区
so next time, we're gonna explore a dynamic vertex buffer
我们如何让每一帧的数据都流进顶点缓冲区
how we can actually every frame stream all of this data into that vertex buffer
然后让它动态地响应任何我们想要的东西
and then have that dynamically respond to anything we want
然后随着本系列的继续，我们也会开始介绍那个渲染器
and then as the series goes on, we'll kind of start introducing that renderer as well
并且那就是我们正在努力的目标
and that's kind of the goal that we're working towards
就像一个完整的批渲染器，它能够处理我们抛出的任何东西
like a full on batch renderer, that's gonna be able to handle anything we throwed it
无论如何，希望大家喜欢这个视频，如果喜欢，请点赞
anyway, hope you guys enjoyed this video, if you did, please hit that like button
不要忘记在patreon.com/TheCherno上支持这个频道
don't forget to help support this channel on patreon.com/TheCherno is the link for that
非常感谢所有人的支持，让这一切成为可能
huge thank you to everyone who does help support this and make this possible
我希望你们和我一样喜欢这个批渲染入门迷你系列
I hope you guys are enjoying this batch entering mini series as much as I have
如果你们有其他想法或任何不明白的地方
if you have any other ideas or anything that you don't understand
请在下方留言，我会尽量回复你们的
please leave a comment below, and I'll try and get back to you
下次见，再见
I will see you guys next time, goodbye